Guide to the Abraham Lincoln Collection [facsimile], 1846-1865 M0024
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Abraham Lincoln Collection [facsimile],
1846-1865
M0024
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
46.0 Items
Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865
Access Restrictions
None.
- Lincoln letters in facsimile (Box 1, Folder A)
  - To three men in answer to an inquiry regarding his "house divided" speech, 1860 Feb. 14
  - To Hon. O. H. Browning. Delaware Indians and railroad right-of-way, 1861 Jan. 20
  - Regarding a petition to free the slaves, 1864 Apr. 15
  - Two letters to Major Thomas T. Eckert relating to the abortive Hampton Roads Peace Conference of Jan. 30 - Feb. 4, 1865
- Lincoln addresses in facsimile (Box 1, Folder B)
  - Sectionalism. Includes information on Lincoln's relationshipe with William W. Wyatt, 1856 Oct. 1.
  - Gettysburg Address, 1863
- Lincoln signature: letter requesting a commission, endorsed by Lincoln, 1863 May 28, 1863 June 1 (Box 1, Folder C)
- Lincoln signature: Appointment signed by Lincoln, 1863 May 19
- National Union Party flyer; and invitation to accompany Lincoln's body to Springfield, 1865 Apr. 20 (Box 1, Folder D)
- Lincoln letters in facsimile (Box 1, Folder E)
  - Lincoln to Dear Doctor [Anson Henry], 1860 Sept. 22; Photostat
  - Lincoln to Cassius M. Clay, 1862 Aug. 12; Printed format
- H. H. Dean letter to his children in which he describes the recent Republican convention just completed in Chicago, 1860 May 27 (Box 1, Folder F)
- Miscellaneous documents (Box 1, Folder G)
  - Bishop Simpson's Lincoln Funeral copy (facsimile) of first publication
  - "Four Days in May," pamphlet re Illinois' participation in funeral
  - Gettysburg Address, facsimile copy
- University of Kentucky Library Lincoln Facsimiles (Box 1, Folder H)
  - #12. Letter to Henry Asbury, 1858 July 31
  - #13. Letter to Horace Greeley, [1861] July 15
  - #14a. Letter to William Herndon, 1848 Feb. 2
  - #14b. Letter to William Herndon, 1848 July 11
  - #18. Telegram to Major General Geo. G. Meade, 1865 Aug. 27
  - #19. Letter to Abraham Jonas, 1860 Feb. 4
  - #20. Letter to Major General Meade, 1865 Sept. 24
  - #22. Letter to Mrs. Amanda H. Hall, 1865 March 20
  - #23. Letter to Edward Everett, 1865 Nov. 20
  - #24 Letter of Sec. of War, 1865 Apr. 10
  - #25 Letter to Maj. Gen. Halleck, 1863 Oct. 16
  - #26 Copy of Gettyburg address
  - #27a Letter to William H. Herndon, 1848 Feb. 2
  - #27b Letter to William H. Herndon, 1848 July 11
  - #28 Part of a mss. in which Lincoln wrote the 12 verses of his favorite poem, "Mortality"
  - #29 "Order of procession at Gettysburg" and "Programme at Gettysburg"
  - #30 Two poems, printed, re Lincoln's death: "The Nation is Weeping" by Louise S. Upham; "Lincoln Lies Sleeping" by Natham Upham
  - Map #7 Map of Kentucky, 1846
- "Andrew Johnson was Southern Unionist," newsclipping from San Jose Mercury, 1972 July 23 (Box 1, Folder I)